Guide to the Douglas V. Cannon papers, [1958-1973?]
Cannon, Douglas V. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Douglas V. Cannon papers, [1958-1973?]
3014
Cannon, Douglas V.,
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed materials, publications, and manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pamphlets, speeches, correspondence, articles, and books, largely authored by Douglas Cannon, relating to land economics and the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, including the Golden Gate and the Los Angeles chapters.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Urban economist.
Douglas V. Cannon held many positions with federal agencies, including the Federal Housing Administration and the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration. He served as International President for the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha from 1967 to 1969, and was a trustee of the Lambda Alpha Foundation. Founder, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, Golden Gate Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Pamphlets, speeches, correspondence, articles, and books, largely authored by Douglas Cannon, relating to land economics and the International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, including the Golden Gate and the Los Angeles chapters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cannon, Douglas V., -1974.; Lambda Alpha International. Golden Gate Chapter.; Lambda Alpha International. Los Angeles Chapter.; Lambda Alpha International. Golden Gate Chapter; Lambda Alpha International. Los Angeles Chapter; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.; United States. Federal Housing Administration.; United States. Federal Housing Administration
Subjects:
Housing.; Land use -- Economic aspects.; Urban economics.; Housing; Land use -- Economic aspects; Urban economics
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Part of Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
CONTAINER LIST
- Highlights, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Market Alerts (MAP), Oct. 1970-Aug. 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Housing Trend Letters #3, July 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Housing Trend Letters #3 cont'd, 1972-Mar. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #1-5, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #6-10, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #11-15, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #16-20, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #21-25, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Economist Letters - 11th District, #26-33, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Market Alert, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Housing Construction and Mortgage Credit Markets, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- FHA - Postal Vacancy Surveys, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Construction Activity, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Homeownership Market, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Published articles, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Economic Indicators, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Economic Indicators, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Need for National Land Use Policy in the U.S. and Canada, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Federal Home Loan Bank Annual Report, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Housing Market Analysis: Tool For S&L Management," in Journal of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, Jan. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "Strength and Weakness of Western Housing Markets," in Land Economics, Nov. 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Lambda Alpha: Its Ideals, Its History and Its Future, Apr. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Need for National Urban Land Use Policy, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Lambda Alpha Meeting Notes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- FHLB 11th District Bulletin, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Organization - Lambda Alpha Society (Chapter Level) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Constitution - Lambda Alpha International Fraternity, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- National Officers - Lambda Alpha International Fraternity, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Organizational - Lambda Alpha Society (misc.), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Crisis Fund, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Membership Certificates, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Quarterly Newsletter - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- By-laws - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Land Economics Foundation, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Roster - Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Archives, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- News and Outlines, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Brochure/Graphics, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Economic Fact Book, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Agenda Articles, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Advance Credit Policy, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Speeches, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Annual Reports of the Bank President, 1960-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Diary of Golden Gate Chapter: Message, By-laws, Rituals, etc., 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Treasurer's Report, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lambda Alpha Chapters - Organizational File, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Lambda Alpha Chapters Info - According to Area (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Journal of Land Economics - Lambda Alpha Biennial Congress, Oct. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Lambda Alpha Biennial Congress, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
- Lambda Alpha Biennial Congress, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Land Economics Foundation, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Grand Council, Golden Gate Misc., Harrington Fund, Letters, Press Releases, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Harrington Fund, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)